# James Gullickson

james.gullickson@gmail.com | 651.307.5758

### Summary

Adaptable full-stack developer with a background in neuroimaging research. Experience working in a highly-regulated environment while developing applications for data collection, analysis, and lab management. Passionate about creating intuitive tools that improve processes and bring value to users.

### Experience

### **Software Developer**

University of Minnesota - Laboratory for NeuroPsychiatric Imaging (LNPI) APR 2020 - Present

- Refactored key elements of our core MVC application into a modernized single page application which interfaces with our REST API.
- Designed and implemented a build and distribution process for our Python Bluetooth local server that communicates with our stimulation hardware.
- Created a continuous delivery process for our cognitive training Electron application that handles deployment to client machines in the field.
- Implemented Zoom chat and video integration for our remote cognitive training and tDCS platform.
- Implemented OAuth login flow for Zoom API authentication.

#### **Software Developer / Study Coordinator**

University of Minnesota - Laboratory for NeuroPsychiatric Imaging (LNPI) OCT 2018 - APR 2020

- Implemented custom library of web-based gamified cognitive training tasks for NIMH-funded clinical trial.
- Debugged complex front-end issues relating to the project's custom-developed task-delivery platform.
- Designed / implemented UI's for internal lab tools including a cognitive training administrator panel and a calendar scheduling interface.
- Organized and facilitated meetings between the development team and principal investigators to gather software requirements and to delegate development workloads.

#### **Research Technician**

University of Minnesota / Minneapolis VA Medical Center JAN 2017 - OCT 2018

- Designed custom structural and functional MRI processing pipelines.
- Interfaced with SQL database to organize data for analyses.
- Presented lab research output at national conferences.
- Operated 3T MRI scans for multiple research studies.

#### Lab Manager

Wesley and Lorene Artz Cognitive Neuroscience Research Center JAN 2016 - JAN 2017

### Skills

JavaScript (+ES6) | React | Redux | Vue | Typescript Python | Flask | PyInstaller CSS3 | Sass | Bootstrap | Bulma | HTML5 | D3 Git | Github | Visual Studio Code Gulp | Webpack | Babel | Mocha | Chai Bash | JSON | SQL | MongoDB | Mongoose Node.js | npm | Express | Electron

### Selected Software Projects

- Zoom API integration for Electron application
- Continuous delivery for Bluetooth server and cognitive training Electron application
- User interfaces for internal lab applications
- Gamified web-based cognitive training tasks

### Education

#### **BA, Psychology**

Hamline University - JAN 2017 | GPA 4.0

### Languages

English | Spanish

## Certifications

**3T Magnet Operator** (Siemens MAGNETOM Prisma) Center for Magnetic Resonance Research FEB 2017 - Present

### Links



#### Github:

github.com/jgullickson



#### LinkedIn:

linkedin.com/in/james-gullickson-35166252



#### Google Scholar:

https://tinyurl.com/socwga4